#### APPLIED MATHEMATICIAN · DATA ANALYST

Flat 5, 44 Zetland Road, Bristol, BS6 7AA, United Kingdom

□ +44 (0) 7397 035953 | ☑ colton.kinstley@gmail.com | 🎓 coltonkinstley.com | ☑ coltonkinstley

## Skills

### **Programming & Technical**

PYTHON, MATLAB, UNIX SHELL

- Ten years using python at the scientific/personal scripting level.
- Moderate experience with neural networks and data analysis using TensorFlow, pandas and numpy libraries.
- Completed a graduate course in numerical mathematics using MATLAB. The primary focus was on numerical methods relating to linear systems.
- Six years using and scripting Zsh & Bash. I have written a number of small shell scripts for personal use. I use git version control and access personal and department servers over ssh.

### Communication

I have developed written communication that is courteous, clear and concise through correspondence with large classes of students, small groups of colleagues and individual supervising professors. I can produce technical writing with specialized symbols using the MFX markup language.

# **Experience**

### **University of Houston Dept. of Mathematics**

Houston, Texas USA

INSTRUCTIONAL ASSISTANT

Sept. 2016 - Jan. 2018

- · Developed and presented 1 hour lectures for a Calculus recitation of 60 students 3 times weekly.
- Evaluated and provided feedback to students in their performance on written assignments, MATLAB code and exams in Calculus, Linear Algebra and Discrete Mathematics.
- Constructed written reports for each graded assignment and exam detailing the method by which credit was attributed and the most common errors or areas that needed improvement.
- Responded to inquires of students regarding the correctness of their solutions and provided feedback on how responses could be made more
  accurate.

### **Austin Community College**

Austin, Texas USA

Senior Supplemental Instruction Leader; Mathematics, Physics, ALEKS Tutor; Bridge Teaching Assistant

Jan. 2014 - Dec. 2015

- Lead group sessions with a focus on metacognition and developing effective learning strategies such as identifying valuable metrics by which to monitor progress.
- · Developed lesson plans covering material in the lecture portion of the course focused on active learning and group problem solving activities.
- Tutored elementary, intermediate and college algebra; trigonometry; precalculus; calculus 1, 2 and 3; ordinary differential equations; linear algebra; discrete mathematics; general and engineering physics.
- ALEKS is an adaptive, artificially-intelligent learning system that provides students with an individualized learning experience.
- Provided individual tutoring to over 100 students at any given time in the ALECKS program, each potentially at a unique stage in their progress.
- Supported an intensive course in basic mathematics intended to rapidly bring returning students to TSI completion in eight 4 hour classroom meetings with a mix of lecture, group practice and individual study.

Private Tutor

Houston & Austin, Texas USA

MATHEMATICS, STANDARDIZED TESTING (GRE, SAT)

Sept. 2014 - Present

- · Provide tailored one-on-one tutelage in mathematics to students over a variety of age ranges and skill levels.
- Create marketing materials for my services and manage all aspects of tutoring sessions including scheduling, location, etc.

## Master Burglar Alarm Co.

Austin, Texas USA

ALARM MONITOR AND TECHNICAL SUPPORT AGENT

Feb. 2010 - Nov. 2015

- Acted as the primary point of contact for property representatives, law enforcement and fire response in the event of alarm activation in over 2,000 residential and commercial buildings across Texas.
- Trained new team members in the responsibilities, security information management system and procedures of the alarm department.

## **Education**

**University of Houston** 

Houston, Texas USA

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS

Jan. 2016 - Dec. 2017

University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor of Business Administration

Arlington, Texas USA Jun. 2004 - May. 2008